<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cathrines | The Procedural Legitimacy Project</title>
    <link>/authors/cathrines/</link>
      <atom:link href="/authors/cathrines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>cathrines</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2019. This is a [NORCE](https://norceresearch.no) project funded by the [Research Council of Norway](https://www.forskningsradet.no/) (project no. 262986). [DIGSSCORE](https://www.uib.no/en/digsscore) serves as the project&#39;s main data generating infrastructure.</copyright>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>cathrines</title>
      <link>/authors/cathrines/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/cathrineh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/cathrineh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cathrine Holst is Professor at Department of Sociology and Human Geography and Research Professor at ARENA Centre for European Studies, University of Oslo. She is also connected to Centre for Research on Gender Equality (CORE), Institute for Social Research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Academic interests
Cathrine Holst&amp;rsquo;s main fields of academic interest are political sociology and democracy research, social and political theory, the role of knowledge and expertise in policy and politics, EU, European integration and the Nordic model, gender policy, feminist theory and gender studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holst is director of the research project EUREX: Expertization of Public Inquiry Commissions in a Europeanized Administrative Order (2016-2020). She is also affiliated with the Horizon 2020-project GLOBUS: Reconsidering European Contributions to Global Justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;sup&gt;2020&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2021&lt;/sub&gt; Holst will be connected to Centre for Advanced Studies (CAS) at the Norwegian Academy of Science and Letters. Holst and Jakob Elster will be leaders of one of the research groups at CAS and the project What is a good policy? Political morality, feasibility and democracy (GOODPOL).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holst has a dr. polit.-degree from University of Bergen (2005). From 2005 to 2007 she was Associate Professor in philosophy of the social sciences, University of Bergen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She has been guest researcher at QoG (Quality of Government), University of Gothenburg (2014), Robert Schuman Centre, European University Institute, Firenze (2012), Hans Jonas-Zentrum, Freie Universität, Berlin (2004), and New School for Social Research, New York (2001)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holst has directed and participated in several research projects. She was member of the Norwegian Gender+ Equality Commission (2010-2012). She is an experienced journal editor and has had columns in several Norwegian newspapers. Holst is member of The Norwegian Academy of Science and Letters, and is currently Head of Board for the Science Studies Colloquium Series at the University of Oslo, see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uio.no/english/research/news-and-events/events/guest-lectures-seminars/science-studies/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.uio.no/english/research/news-and-events/events/guest-lectures-seminars/science-studies/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
