<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Procedural Legitimacy Project</title>
    <link>/authors/hannahw/</link>
      <atom:link href="/authors/hannahw/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>The Procedural Legitimacy Project</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2019. This is a [NORCE](https://norceresearch.no) project funded by the [Research Council of Norway](https://www.forskningsradet.no/) (project no. 262986). [DIGSSCORE](https://www.uib.no/en/digsscore) serves as the project&#39;s main data generating infrastructure.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>The Procedural Legitimacy Project</title>
      <link>/authors/hannahw/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The importance of good loser messages – A de-biasing experiment</title>
      <link>/publication/esaiasson/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/esaiasson/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/hannahw/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/hannahw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a PhD candidate in political science at the University of Amsterdam and the KU Leuven (joint degree). I obtained a masters degree in communication science from the research master program at the University of Amsterdam and a bachelors degree in communication studies and economics from the University of Mannheim. In 2016 I was awarded a 4-Year fellowship from the FWO – Research Foundation Flanders (Belgium) for a research project on democratic innovations. My PhD is supervised by Prof. Sofie Marien and Prof. Wouter van der Brug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am interested in political psychology and political behavior, particularly in the development and the decline of perceived democratic legitimacy. In my PhD project, I investigate the often-stated potential of democratic innovations to reconnect citizens to political authorities and to tackle an acclaimed legitimacy deficit with a specific focus on winners and losers of democratic decisions. I am also interested in political consumerism and in the role of political fact-checking during election campaigns in shaping political trust. Methodologically, I use mainly experimental methods and comparative survey analysis but I am also interested in qualitative approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
