<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Procedural Legitimacy Project</title>
    <link>/authors/erikk/</link>
      <atom:link href="/authors/erikk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>The Procedural Legitimacy Project</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2019. This is a [NORCE](https://norceresearch.no) project funded by the [Research Council of Norway](https://www.forskningsradet.no/) (project no. 262986). [DIGSSCORE](https://www.uib.no/en/digsscore) serves as the project&#39;s main data generating infrastructure.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>The Procedural Legitimacy Project</title>
      <link>/authors/erikk/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Supply-side Determinants of Populism: A Conjoint Experiment in France, Germany, the Netherlands, Norway, Iceland, and Sweden</title>
      <link>/publication/arnesen-populist-conjoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/arnesen-populist-conjoint/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/erikk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/erikk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Erik Knudsen is a postdoctoral fellow at the Digital Social Science Core Facility (DIGSSCORE). He holds a PhD from the Department of Information Science and Media Studies at the University of Bergen, Norway. Much of Knudsens research explores patterns and effects of news and political communication, trust in journalism, and selective exposure to like-minded information. He is founder and PI of the Norwegian Journalism Panel and the interdisciplinary Political Communication Research Group at DIGSSCORE (together with Stefan Dahlberg). His work has appeared in Political Communication, Journalism, and other peer-reviewed journals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Qualifications: Journalism, political communication, selective exposure, framing, agenda setting, media effects, news values, media logics and mediatisation of politics, quantitative content analysis, experimental research design, public opinion and survey research.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
