<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors | The Procedural Legitimacy Project</title>
    <link>/authors/</link>
      <atom:link href="/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Authors</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2019. This is a [NORCE](https://norceresearch.no) project funded by the [Research Council of Norway](https://www.forskningsradet.no/) (project no. 262986). [DIGSSCORE](https://www.uib.no/en/digsscore) serves as the project&#39;s main data generating infrastructure.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>/authors/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a political scientist who takes an interest in political behavior, public opinion, and elections, with a main methodological focus on experimental studies. Currently I lead the projects &lt;em&gt;Can Fair Decision Making Procedures Increase The Legitimacy of Democracies?&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Democratic innovation in practice&lt;/em&gt;. Together with Yvette Peters, I coordinate the research group on Political Behavior and Democracy at the Digital Social Science Core Facilities &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;http://digsscore.uib.no&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DIGSSCORE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/hannahw/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/hannahw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a PhD candidate in political science at the University of Amsterdam and the KU Leuven (joint degree). I obtained a masters degree in communication science from the research master program at the University of Amsterdam and a bachelors degree in communication studies and economics from the University of Mannheim. In 2016 I was awarded a 4-Year fellowship from the FWO – Research Foundation Flanders (Belgium) for a research project on democratic innovations. My PhD is supervised by Prof. Sofie Marien and Prof. Wouter van der Brug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am interested in political psychology and political behavior, particularly in the development and the decline of perceived democratic legitimacy. In my PhD project, I investigate the often-stated potential of democratic innovations to reconnect citizens to political authorities and to tackle an acclaimed legitimacy deficit with a specific focus on winners and losers of democratic decisions. I am also interested in political consumerism and in the role of political fact-checking during election campaigns in shaping political trust. Methodologically, I use mainly experimental methods and comparative survey analysis but I am also interested in qualitative approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/jonasl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/jonasl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jonas Linde bio here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/mikajoh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/mikajoh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mikael bio her&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/petere/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/petere/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My main interest is in practical democratic politics. What makes democracy work, and how can we make it work even better?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/troysb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/troysb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Troy bio her&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/asno/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/asno/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Åsta bio here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/elisabethi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/elisabethi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Elisabeth Ivarsflaten is a Professor in the Department of Comparative Politics at the University of Bergen. She is the principal investigator of the Digital Social Science Core Facility (DIGSSCORE) and the Norwegian Citizen Panel at the University of Bergen.  She holds a Ph.D. from the University of Oxford and was a Postdoctoral Prize Research Fellow at Nuffield College, Oxford, before joining the University of Bergen faculty.
Ivarsflaten specializes in the study of public opinion and political parties. Her research has appeared in the American Journal of Political Science, Comparative Political Studies, the European Journal of Political Research, and other peer-reviewed journals. Much of Ivarsflaten research, teaching and writing explores radical extreme right parties and social movements. She has also been engaged for many years in the development and application of innovative survey research. More recently she has been branching out to the field of law and politics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/erikk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/erikk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Erik Knudsen is a postdoctoral fellow at the Digital Social Science Core Facility (DIGSSCORE). He holds a PhD from the Department of Information Science and Media Studies at the University of Bergen, Norway. Much of Knudsens research explores patterns and effects of news and political communication, trust in journalism, and selective exposure to like-minded information. He is founder and PI of the Norwegian Journalism Panel and the interdisciplinary Political Communication Research Group at DIGSSCORE (together with Stefan Dahlberg). His work has appeared in Political Communication, Journalism, and other peer-reviewed journals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Qualifications: Journalism, political communication, selective exposure, framing, agenda setting, media effects, news values, media logics and mediatisation of politics, quantitative content analysis, experimental research design, public opinion and survey research.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/liseb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/liseb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bio Lise her&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/dominikd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/dominikd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I study voting behavior and political competition in representative democracies with a special focus on how social identity relationships influence citizens&amp;rsquo; choices. My work lies at the intersection of Political Economy, Political Behavior, Experimental Methods, and Political Psychology.
In my research I build on strategic and behavioral theories of voting and implement experiments to analyze how individuals evaluate their politicians&amp;rsquo; performance, when they discriminate in favor of their social group, how they make redistributive allocation decisions, or how they coordinate their choices with their peers when forming electoral coalitions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/yvettep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/yvettep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yvette&amp;rsquo;s research concerns democracies, how they work, how they change, and in what way institutions affect citizen behaviour in them. This past and ongoing research can be summarized in four segments:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Political representation, responsiveness and inequality”
This project aims to better understand the relationship between citizens and their representatives in democracies. Democracy requires a certain level of congruence between what citizens want and what representatives do is required. One aspect in this perspective is the congruence between the preferences of the citizens and their (regional or party) representative; another is the congruence between people’s preferences and actual policy output; and yet another is the differentiated responsiveness of representatives—policies may favor some groups more than others. These types of relationships are central in this study, including the possible effects that different political institutions (e.g. electoral system; referendums; executive-legislative relation) may have on the level of congruence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Restructuring democracy: ever increasing or perpetual crisis?”
This project looks at the development of democracies over time, but also at the way that democracy functions when it includes a specific combination of democratic elements. Democracies all over the world have changed in their institutional structure—both incrementally and in big steps. Considering these changes and the challenges that democracies have had to deal with over time, the shape of democracy seems to have changed. This project aims to see how they have changed, whether we can now distinguish a different type of democracy, and whether we may observe different clusters of democracies moving in different directions, in a quantitative way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The impact of diffusion of politics on political participation”
This project focuses on the implications of institutional change in democracies between 1980 and 2005. The political system, and the way that governments deal with the distribution of public goods, seems to have changed over time. Although national governments still deal with many political issues, a lot of tasks have been delegated to other instances. The aim of this project is to see whether different types of authority diffusion (horizontal, vertical, diagonal) have had an impact on levels and changes in levels of different forms of political participation (representative, extra-representative and direct), and to what extent these changes transformed democracy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The impact of intra-EU migration on welfare state attitudes&amp;rdquo;
As part of the project &amp;lsquo;Labour migration and moral sustainability of the Norwegian welfare state&amp;rsquo; (directed by Stein Kuhnle and Cornelius Cappelen; funded by the Norwegian Research council), we investigate the extend that within-EU migration affects how people think about their own welfare state. Also comparing with other forms of immigration, we try to find out whether citizens are more/less supportive of welfare schemes, whether they become more protective or exclusive/inclusive, and in what way institutional structures affect such relationships.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/eiriks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/eiriks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Eirik bio here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/ninas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/ninas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nina bio here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/sigvet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/sigvet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sigve Tjøtta bio here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/berntaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/berntaa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bio (in Norwegian language):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bernt Aardal, f. 1950, er mag.art. i statsvitenskap ved Universitetet i Oslo 1979 (med historie og sosiologi støttefag) og dr. philos. i statsvitenskap samme sted 1993. Han har vært tilknyttet Valgforskningsprogrammet ved Institutt for samfunnsforskning (ISF) siden 1975 og ledet programmet siden 1985. Vitenskapelig assistent  ved Valgforskningsprogrammet, Institutt for samfunnsforskning 1975-83. Visiting Scholar ved Center for Political Studies, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan 1983-84. Forskningsstipendiat NAVF 1984-86. Forskningsleder ved ISF 1994-2009. Forsker I ved ISF 2009-2013. Førsteamanuensis II 1994-1998 og professor II 1998-2013 ved Institutt for statsvitenskap, Universitetet i Oslo. Ansatt som professor samme sted fra 2013. Bistilling ved Institutt for samfunnsforskning fra 2013. Han har undervist ved universiteter og høyskoler, og skrevet en rekke bøker og artikler om valg, holdningsdannelse, offentlig opinion og valgordninger. Han var medlem av Valglovutvalget i 1997-2001 og er medlem av Valglovutvalget 2017-2019. Han ledet også et utvalg som utredet innføring av elektronisk stemmegivning, nedsatt av Kommunal- og regionaldepartementet, 2004-2005. Styreleder for Norsk senter for forskningsdata (NSD) 2003-2010 og styreleder for Institutt for fredsforskning 2007-2017. Medlem av Scientific Advisory Board, CESSDA (Consortium of European Social Science Data Archives), 2014-.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/dach/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/dach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dag Arne has a Dr. Philos degree in comparative politics from the University of Bergen in 1999. His research experience and interests covers the study of political participation, representation, opinion formation, electoral systems, quantitative methods and experimental research designs. His publications includes topic such as turnout, satisfaction with public services, and citizens&amp;rsquo; reactions to terrorism.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/johannesb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/johannesb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Johannes Bergh is the head of the Norwegian National Election Studies (NNES) program at the Institute for Social Research. His research interests include political participation, experimental designs, voting, political behavior among minorities, electoral systems and democratic innovations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/gautet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/gautet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gaute Torsvik bio here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/stefand/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/stefand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dahlberg&amp;rsquo;s research focuses on representative democracy, democratic legitimacy, political parties and voting behavior. He is currently working on two research projects. The first project is related to democratic legitimacy in a country comparative perspective while the second project deals with gender differences in voting support for xenophobic parties.
Dahlberg teaches quantitative methods at Ph.D. and Masters level at the International Administration and Global Governance program, University of Gothenburg and Quantitative Methods - Multivariate Analysis at the Faculty of Social Sciences, Lund University&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/cathrineh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/cathrineh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cathrine Holst is Professor at Department of Sociology and Human Geography and Research Professor at ARENA Centre for European Studies, University of Oslo. She is also connected to Centre for Research on Gender Equality (CORE), Institute for Social Research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Academic interests
Cathrine Holst&amp;rsquo;s main fields of academic interest are political sociology and democracy research, social and political theory, the role of knowledge and expertise in policy and politics, EU, European integration and the Nordic model, gender policy, feminist theory and gender studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holst is director of the research project EUREX: Expertization of Public Inquiry Commissions in a Europeanized Administrative Order (2016-2020). She is also affiliated with the Horizon 2020-project GLOBUS: Reconsidering European Contributions to Global Justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;sup&gt;2020&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2021&lt;/sub&gt; Holst will be connected to Centre for Advanced Studies (CAS) at the Norwegian Academy of Science and Letters. Holst and Jakob Elster will be leaders of one of the research groups at CAS and the project What is a good policy? Political morality, feasibility and democracy (GOODPOL).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holst has a dr. polit.-degree from University of Bergen (2005). From 2005 to 2007 she was Associate Professor in philosophy of the social sciences, University of Bergen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She has been guest researcher at QoG (Quality of Government), University of Gothenburg (2014), Robert Schuman Centre, European University Institute, Firenze (2012), Hans Jonas-Zentrum, Freie Universität, Berlin (2004), and New School for Social Research, New York (2001)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holst has directed and participated in several research projects. She was member of the Norwegian Gender+ Equality Commission (2010-2012). She is an experienced journal editor and has had columns in several Norwegian newspapers. Holst is member of The Norwegian Academy of Science and Letters, and is currently Head of Board for the Science Studies Colloquium Series at the University of Oslo, see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uio.no/english/research/news-and-events/events/guest-lectures-seminars/science-studies/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.uio.no/english/research/news-and-events/events/guest-lectures-seminars/science-studies/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/danieli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/danieli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Daniel bio her.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/heli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/heli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My research interests are judicial behavior, judicial dissent, and public opinion of courts and judges. I focus mainly on the case of the Supreme Court of Norway, but have also researched the Danish Supreme Court. My work mainly consist of quantitative and survey experimental analyses. My most recent publication is &amp;ldquo;Dissent, Legitimacy, and Public Support for Court Decisions: Evidence from a Survey‐Based Experiment&amp;rdquo;, Law &amp;amp; Society Review, 53(2): 588-610.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/josk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/josk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jon Kåre bio here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/martar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/martar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bio Marta her&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cathrines</title>
      <link>/authors/cathrines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/cathrines/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
